[Bhak] This isn't going as planned.
We thought we had more time
to teach you how to dive.
However, the rescuers have decided
it's better to get you out sooner instead.
This means Dr. Harry will be back
with a foreign diver in a few hours.
That means they're going
to start taking you home today.
[boys yelling excitedly]
What do you mean
by things not going as planned?
You will put on a wetsuit, dive gear,
that part is the same.
Then you'll take a relaxer.
It'll be an easy pill to swallow.
Then Dr. Harry will give you
a shot that will put you to sleep.
Then one of the divers
will swim you out of the cave.
When you wake up,
you'll finally be outside again.
They should let us practice a little more.
Even I'm getting better at diving now.
[Bhak] We know, but the cave is…
It's more challenging than we realized.
The last thing we want
is to put you in a position
you are not prepared for.
These divers are complete experts.
They're the best in the world.
And they already figured everything out.
This is a good way
to get everyone out of here
as safely as we can.
How will you decide
who should be the first to go?
There are a lot
of very important decisions
being made for you right now.
So I thought
you should have the right to choose.
Talk it over with Coach Eak.
Let me know what you decide.
No rush. Take your time.
Okay?
Be right back.
[boys sighing]
The fairest way would probably be
to go from oldest to youngest.
I agree.
Or youngest to oldest?
[Titan] I'd show you how it's done.
But I owe Baitoey one last chance
at checkers redemption.
[boys chuckling]
I'll go first.
Are you sure, Mark?
You are brave.
I wanna get out of here.
[Eak] Dr. Bhak,
is this really safe?
It's as safe as it can be.
Then, I wanna go first.
If I die,
then they can think of a new plan.
This plan is the last option.
It's the best option,
but you can't be the one to go first.
If things go badly,
the boys are going to need you
in here.
[Buddhist monks chanting]
[theme music playing]
[air hisses]
[man] What are you doing calling me today?
[Harry] Can't a son just call his old man?
[Dad] Not when your mug's
all over the bloody Advertiser.
Going on about you and Craig
and some adventure in Thailand.
"Adventure." That what they're calling it?
[Dad chuckles]
[Dad] Good on you, Bertie Boy.
Listen, Dad.
Odds are not all of them
are gonna make it,
and… I thought I was prepared
to live with those consequences,
but the closer it gets…
I don't know.
[Dad grumbles]
I mean, what if the first boy dies?
Yeah, but what if the next 12 live?
What would you do in my position?
Uh…
I don't know.
But if it was you or my grandson in there…
[Craig] Harry.
They're ready.
Is that the real Dr. Harris?
I'll see you in the command tent.
Is that Craig? When are you gonna
get yourself some decent friends?
Uh, soon, Dad. Soon.
Listen…
-I'll call you later when it's all over.
-Well, you better.
What good is having somebody on the inside
if I have to be glued to the news
all night to find out what's going on?
Love you, Dad.
Love you, Bert.
[exhales]
[Narongsak] This is a moon shot.
We all know it.
[thunder rumbles]
[Narongsak] The coming storm
is worse than anything we've seen before.
I'm an engineer by training.
So I'm accustomed to risk-reward analysis.
Right now, we understand
the risk to the boys
and that we have to seize this moment
while the weather and water
are still in our favor
if we are to have a chance to save them.
But, if at any point,
the risk-reward ratio
tilts against us,
I will have no choice
but to call off the mission immediately
before the coming storm
endangers all your lives.
I want everyone to memorize this word.
Landslide.
[in Thai] Landslide.
[in English] Major Hensen.
That's the watchword
for immediate evacuation.
You hear that,
you get the hell out of there.
The conditions in the cave
can change rapidly,
and we can't risk
more people getting trapped.
Ranger Pim.
We'll be keeping a hyper-accurate watch
of the weather and water levels,
at the dam, pump,
and pipes throughout the camp.
All good down here!
[pipe groaning]
[Chet] The SEALs
will be running point in chamber 1
alongside the Chiang Mai Rescue Squad.
They'll be medevacked
to a hospital in Chiang Rai.
The boys' health is already fragile.
We'll keep them isolated
even from their families,
so they aren't exposed
to any more potential illnesses.
[parents clamoring]
John and I will be escorting
the boys one by one
along with David Ellsworth.
[John] The rest of our team
will be positioned throughout the cave
for support with tank changes
and anything else we may need.
[Rick] We'll be handing off the boys
to Captain Anan Surawan
and the SEALs in chamber 3.
Once inside,
we'll be taking our cues from Harry.
I'll be giving the boys
Xanax to relax them
before an injection of ketamine.
Ketamine really is the safest way
to keep them breathing and unconscious.
You need to check the boys
in each chamber,
but you need to keep them moving
unless you detect them waking.
We gotta get them out.
No matter what.
[ethereal music playing]
[Charles] We all know
what the chances are here.
If something goes wrong
once you're in that water,
as bad as it sounds,
it's better we bring out
one body than two.
As Harry says, no matter what,
you keep moving.
[Craig] Remember once you're in there,
you're just a doctor with a patient.
Like you've been
thousands of times before.
This is not the time to be the director
of feelings and emotions.
Well, I can't promise anything,
but I'll see what I can do.
Rick.
[Rick] Harry.
Hey, Doc.
We've already got a problem.
[clears throat]
Can you tell him not to worry?
They'll bring another mask
on the next time around.
[softly] Aren't these already
the smallest ones you could find?
[uneasy music playing]
Don't worry, Mark. We'll get another one.
[Eak] Note.
Note,
he's next in line.
Followed by Tle, Nick, and Mix after him.
They chose the order.
They have decided to go with whoever lives
the farthest from the cave,
so they can tell each other's parents
they're coming home.
[Harry chuckles]
Note is going to be the first.
-See you.
-[boys saying goodbye]
[Harry] Okay.
Let's get his gear on.
Okay. You give him the pill.
[Mark coughing]
-Send him down to me. I'll be waiting.
-Okay.
[boys saying goodbye to Note]
[Eak] Everyone.
Gather around.
You ready?
One, two, three!
[all] Wild Boars, hey!
[poignant music playing]
[boys chattering]
[Note] Thanks, guys.
See you outside. Okay?
[SEAL] Take it easy.
Slowly.
[Harry] Here we go.
Nice and easy. Here we go.
Okay. I'm gonna give you a jab in the leg.
[SEAL] He's giving you an injection.
You may feel a little sting,
but you'll be okay.
You ready?
[Baitoey] It'll be okay.
You'll be all right.
Go home and see Mum and Dad
very soon, okay?
Here we go.
Off we go.
Lay him down first. Hold tight.
-[SEAL] Here.
-For the feet.
Hold his head.
One. Two.
Three.
Four.
-Go on. Breathe, kid, breathe.
-[Harry] Five.
-Six.
-What's he doing, Doc?
[Harry] Seven…
Even unconscious, the body will
automatically hold its breath underwater.
[Harry sighs] Okay.
Let's get him hooked up.
Craig'll be in the next chamber
to check his vitals
and top him up if need be.
[Bhak] Get set.
Remember the only way this works
is to keep moving forward.
Good luck.
[tense music playing]
EMERGENCY CENTER
[all chattering]
[reporter 1] People have gathered
at temples throughout Thailand…
[reporter 2] It's unclear
what kind of medical attention
the boys and their coach will need
once they've been removed from the cave.
But after 18 days of starvation,
one can only imagine.
[reporter 3] After the plan
to rescue the boys from the cave…
…school children have suspended classes
to pray for the boys' safe return
to their families.
Everyone nervously awaits
the first rescue from the cave.
[Luke] Fish on the line!
It's going down!
SKED's going down, guys! Relay that!
We want jacks in the whole way down.
That's it, folks.
[SEALs speaking Thai]
One of the boys is coming out!
[people clamoring]
[Chet] Hurry!
Is he all right?
[suspenseful music playing]
3RD INFANTRY BATTALION
17TH INFANTRY REGIMENT
[reporters clamoring]
-Come on. Come on.
-[reporter] Let's go and talk to him.
[reporters clamoring excitedly]
[reporter] Governor!
[Narongsak] A few minutes ago,
the first of the Wild Boars
was extracted from the cave
alive!
[jubilant music playing]
He's en route to a hospital in Chiang Rai
after a grueling
five-hour rescue operation.
We're waiting on an update
on his condition.
[reporter] Tell me the name
of the first boy!
Thank you.
[reporters clamoring]
[man] Clear the way!
Another Wild Boar's here.
[sirens wailing]
[Biw's dad] They brought out
five boys alive so far.
They won't say who, but there's a problem.
I bumped into one of the officers.
We used to work together back in the day.
I got him to talk.
He told me…
they didn't have a mask
for the smallest boy.
[Tai emotionally] Titan.
[Biw's mom] Tai, take it easy.
Titan is the youngest,
but you think he's the smallest?
He isn't.
[Harry sighs] Sorry, little mate.
Not yet.
We will find a mask
that fits you, Mark. Next time.
[Harris pats Mark]
[Mark coughing]
[Bhak] His chest condition
is getting worse.
Night's too.
But it isn't as bad as Mark's yet.
[Harry] Well, he's older and stronger.
I think he'll be okay.
[Mark coughing hoarsely]
[thunder rumbles]
[Bhak] You're last up, Night.
Have some water.
[Mark] What about the rest of us?
You will go out tomorrow morning.
-[Night] I'll save you some cake.
-[Titan] No need.
Tonight, we feast on all the rations
those suckers left behind.
[boys chuckling]
Wild Boars, fight on!
[all] Fight on!
[Mark coughing]
[Bhak] Let's go.
[mumbling] Mom,
save me some SpongeBob.
[chuckles] Did he say
something about SpongeBob?
All right, let's go!
I think he'll be okay,
but keep an eye on his breath. Set?
See you out there.
So far…
this is our best option.
It looks like a kid's toy.
[Charles] It's worse.
That's not a positive-pressure mask.
It's the only thing we found that'll
fit over his face.
We have to give
the divers a break tonight,
but we should be able to rig it
so that it holds tight by morning.
That long?
[Appakorn] The divers have been
in the cave for 12 hours.
They are exhausted.
If we push them any further,
we will increase the risk factor.
[Mark coughs]
What if they don't come back for us?
No way, man.
They're not gonna leave us in here, Mark.
[yells] I didn't say
they'd do it on purpose!
They're hiding how bad it is
'cause they don't wanna scare us!
You don't have to yell at Phong
because you're scared!
I'm not scared!
[mocking Mark]
-[Mark grunts]
-[Eak] That's enough! Mark!
That's it.
You too.
We are in this together
until the very end.
Understood?
[Mark coughing]
[diver] What's wrong with him?
I swam as hard as I could.
Couldn't feel him breathing.
-Is he the one that's sick?
-His nose is definitely blocked.
[Craig] Hey, Terry! Move!
-[Harry] What's happening?
-[Craig] He's barely breathing.
[Harry] Craig, did you administer
any more drugs?
-[Craig] No.
-[Harry] Okay, good.
Tilt his chin up.
Keep his airways open.
Has anyone got a blanket?
[Rick] Too much on the first dose?
Maybe.
Hard to say, really.
He does have a chest infection
I may have underestimated.
Need to get his core temperature up.
Craig, we'll do a breath count.
-[watch beeps]
-One. Two. Three.
-Come on, kid.
-[Craig] Four. Five. Six.
-[Harry] That's one.
-Seven. Eight. Nine. Ten.
[growing distant]
Eleven. Twelve. Thirteen.
-[Harry] Come on.
-[Craig] Fourteen…
[Luke on radio] Still no sign of Night.
[gadget beeps]
Harry, we need to keep moving.
Okay, breathing's stable.
That'll have to do.
Let's move!
What if I have to give him
another dose on the way?
-Then, you give him another dose.
-If he stops breathing again?
Look, the best chance he's got
is to get him outta here
as fast as possible.
[Rick] Okay.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Luke] Fish on the line!
SKED's going down!
[SEAL 1, in Thai] Watch your step.
[suspenseful music continues]
[SEAL 2, in Thai] Hurry! Go Quick!
[siren wailing]
[man, in Thai] Here comes a Wild Boar!
[in Thai] Here he comes.
[crowd clamoring]
[helicopter whirring]
[music climaxing]
[Harry gasping] What's happening?
Night's still breathing.
We're getting him to the hospital now.
[Harry sighs]
[UK reporter] As the day ends
in Northern Thailand,
another boy is free.
[German anchor 1] Eight boys have been
successfully rescued from the cave,
but the mission
has been paused until morning.
[German anchor 2] Thanks, Barbara.
The world will have to wait
to know the fate
of the last four boys and their coach.
[siren wailing]
[Harry] The oldest boy,
we brought him out tonight.
I almost couldn't save him.
The little one, Mark,
his chest infection is even worse.
I don't know whether
I can go back in again,
knowing he probably won't make it.
I mean, I've lost patients before, but…
We don't make a habit
of putting them in danger to start with.
You know, I was thinking
about that day on the boat as a kid.
I really do have a habit of biting off
more than I can chew, don't I?
You think that's why
I tell you that story, do you?
[chuckles] Oh God.
Look,
anyone can get lost at sea, Son.
Nothing special about that.
But you…
You went out on that boat again
after you had the crap scared out of you.
Thought you were gonna be fish food.
And you went diving again.
Now that's when I knew
what sort of a man you were gonna be.
Hey, listen,
the nurse told me that you had a fall,
and you didn't remember it.
Dad, you could've had a stroke.
You should've told me.
Why? You'd be on the next plane back.
So you can faff off about this
nursing home,
making everybody nervous.
We all know I'm gonna be fine.
Now stop worrying about me,
and start worrying about
whether you're gonna go down
that cave again tomorrow or not.
It's not like they're gonna
leave you here by yourself, Mark.
Leave me alone, Titan.
Whoa! That's amazing.
Wild Boar roster for all time?
Do my name at the top!
[moodily] It's in order
of who's getting rescued.
Never mind, then.
All right, put me on last.
For me, it's not the worst to go last.
Oh yeah?
So brave of you not to be afraid at all.
That's right. I'm a badass.
You have no idea
what it's like being the last to go.
Or to be looked at
like you're weak when you're not.
Just once, I wanted to prove
that I'm actually brave enough.
But now…
I may never get out of here.
[thunder rumbling]
[Kelly] The water is picking up speed.
Fifteen millimeters per hour and rising.
[Pim] He'll call off the rescue.
[gadget beeps]
[Kelly] In the next couple of hours,
it'll pummel the divers.
At this rate,
the smaller chambers
will flood completely.
Those who dive in tomorrow
may never come out.
[somber music playing]
[thunder rumbling]
[solemnly] The risk-reward ratio
has tipped against us,
leaving us to face a stark choice.
No one's leaving those boys to die.
[tense music playing]
The rising water is going to change
the topography of the swim.
There'll be new chambers
you could get lost in,
passages may become blocked with sand.
Even if you're just prepping air tanks,
this will be
the most dangerous water we've faced.
[Charles] First kid took
nearly five hours to get out.
By the end of the day,
we had that down to almost two.
If we have any chance at all
to beat this storm,
today… we need to do that in 90 minutes.
[Bhak] The cave is flooding.
And with the coming storm,
every second counts.
Circumstances have changed.
You must go now.
You need to leave
while the divers still have the strength
to carry your weight out of here.
We had an agreement.
I would go last
in case something went wrong.
[Bhak] I know.
You know if something happens,
they will all understand.
I promised to keep them all safe.
[Bhak] Eak,
you're a hero.
The boys all believe it.
And we all do too.
[dramatic music playing]
[Bhak] Boys,
it's your coach's turn.
But your coach refuses to leave.
Help me here.
-[Tee] Please go, Eak.
-[Titan] Come on, Eak.
[Phong] You have to.
[Mark] Please go, Eak.
Don't worry about us. We'll be okay.
[Bhak] See?
None of them hesitated.
Eak, it's time to go.
Now.
We'll see you on the other side.
[sobs]
[breathes deeply]
[sniffs]
[Bhak] Here.
-[Tee] Don't worry.
-[Titan] Keep it up. You can do this.
You can do this.
[Mark] Don't worry, coach.
[Titan] Fight on.
[Bhak sniffs]
-[Phong] Good luck.
-[Titan] Good luck. You can do this.
[poignant music playing]
Do your best.
[music swells]
[Eak softly] See you soon. [sniffs]
[Eak breathing shakily]
See you soon.
[Bhak muffled] Harry, you okay?
Harry?
Yeah.
You got kids?
A son.
What would you tell him if you knew
he might not get out of this cave?
I'd do what every parent would do.
I'd tell him not to worry.
Yeah.
What's wrong?
What's wrong with you?
I'm afraid of drowning.
You may drown here,
but it's better to try.
I'm gonna hug my mom, eat real food, and--
Take a bath?
Wouldn't you risk the possibility
of maybe being able
to do those things again,
rather than sitting here
and worrying about what might happen?
[Bhak] Titan.
You're up.
[Mark] My mother once told me
that courage isn't about not being afraid,
you can be afraid,
but you still keep moving.
I left you something over there.
[Mark crying softly]
[voice cracks] Titan.
MARK
[Bhak] I can't guarantee
that you're going to make it.
But the water is rising.
If you stay here,
I can guarantee that you will die.
We have to go, Titan.
Think of home.
[Harry] Okay, he's out.
What's all this?
[men chuckling]
There's gotta be four or five of them.
-Cool Ranch Dorito MREs.
-[Harry chuckles]
[diver chuckling]
[Harry] Need a breather?
[Rick] No.
Water's starting to push back
at the T-junction.
We've got to go.
[Harry] Okay. Let's move.
NAMES OF MISSING PEOPLE
[tense music playing]
[music intensifying]
[music stops]
[Harry] There we go.
[Harry struggling with mask straps]
Take it off.
[mask being removed]
[Harry] Where's that foam?
[Baitoey] Listen to me, Mark.
This will hurt a little.
We have to make sure this will work.
We're gonna get you out of here, okay?
[Harry] Hold it there.
[Baitoey] Okay.
You good?
[Harry] Sorry we haven't got something
better for you.
[Mark] Well, Dr. Harry, I'm ready now.
I'm ready to go.
Let's find out our fate.
[Bhak sighs] He…
He's ready.
We have to find out our fate.
He's right.
Think it's about time
we all left this cave.
There's no pressure in the mask, Doc.
If water gets in, he'll drown.
We'd best keep him steady, then.
Yeah.
[Harry] Good boy.
I can do this.
Best get your own gear on.
Don't worry. We're right behind you.
We're moving.
John's heading Mark
over to David in chamber 6,
so they don't lose time
on the cylinder change.
[Harry] What the hell
are you still doing here?
I'm waiting for you, of course.
[Harry] That was dumb.
[tense dramatic music playing]
Our sources on the ground have confirmed
conditions in the cave
are more dangerous than ever.
The last boy
is on his journey out of the cave now.
Sources claim that there's an issue
with the smallest boy's mask,
although what that means
for the rescue is still unclear.
-[thud]
-[David groans]
[David grunts]
[David groans]
[Harry] Hey! Let's get moving.
We're still waiting on the last boy.
The last boy? No, he was in front of me.
He hasn't come through yet.
Okay. Everyone. Out of here. Now.
Harry! Mate! You can't go back.
If you run into Bhak or a SEAL,
you'll get yourself killed.
Appakorn was right.
Half of the chambers
are almost flooded already.
Get moving.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Harry gasping]
[suspenseful music continues]
-Fish on!
-[Craig] All right, let's go!
-[Luke] Baitoey! We got Baitoey!
-[Baitoey gasping]
-[SEAL] Yeah?
-[Baitoey] Yeah.
[chuckles with relief]
[David] I hit a sandbar
and just about drowned him.
[Harry] Look, it happens.
Water levels are rising.
Plugs are all over the place.
-[David sighs]
-Are you all right?
[David] The kid.
His breathing's so shallow.
He's gonna need another dose.
He'll stop breathing.
At this stage,
he's more likely to wake
and kill you both.
[David chuckles anxiously]
Hey. Hey.
Hey.
Listen.
I'm gonna take him, okay?
Find the guideline.
Close your eyes.
The water and silt will only distract you.
Close your eyes,
and you feel for that rope, okay?
-[David] All right.
-Off you go.
[David] Okay.
All right, Mark.
Don't stop breathing on me now.
[dramatic music playing]
[water gurgling inside mask]
[music intensifying]
There! There, there, there, there!
[SEAL] Good luck.
[Luke] Welcome back, Mike.
There's Bhak.
We've got all the SEALs back.
[engine powers down]
The engine stalled again.
[music becomes increasingly dramatic]
[Kelly] No, no, no, no.
[Craig] Come on, Harry.
[water rushing]
[Luke shouts] We have to go now!
[Baitoey] Wait! Hold on!
There's another boy left!
[Luke] Core team remains!
Everyone else out!
Landslide!
Everyone out! Move! Move! Move!
Landslide! Let's go!
Landslide!
Out now! Out now!
[groans]
[SEAL] We've only reached the ridge!
[groaning]
[men yelling]
Landslide! Landslide!
Keep them out! Keep them out!
[SEAL] You can't enter! I'm sorry.
Mark!
[dramatic music playing]
[Harry grunts]
[Harry groans]
[people clamoring loudly]
[Harry] Come on, little mate.
Just one more to go.
Just one… more… to go.
[climactic music playing]
Mark!
[music intensifies]
[air tank scraping]
-[Harry grunts]
-[air tank clanks]
[people yelling in panic]
[no audible dialogue]
-[air tank scraping]
-[Harry grunting]
[somber music playing]
[music intensifies]
[metallic clank]
[sound becomes muffled]
Mark!
[medic 1] Table! Hurry! Hurry!
[medic 2, in Thai] Quick!
We got the boy!
[muffled sound continues]
Mark!
[sobbing]
Mark! [crying out]
[muffled sound continues]
[sound returns to normal]
[poignant music playing]
-[Bhak laughing]
-[Namhom crying]
[laughing]
[men laughing]
[crying] Oh, Mark!
My baby!
[people chuckling]
You rescue this boy?
-Everyone rescue.
-[diver chuckles]
[dramatic music playing]
[crowd chattering]
Thirteen Wild Boars!
They're all alive!
[thunderous cheering]
[cheering continues]
Yes! Yes!
Governor!
We did it.
[rousing music plays]
[Craig] Didn't know
if you two were gonna make it.
You know, I reckon that
the real Dr. Harris would be proud.
[rousing music continues]
[cheering continues]
[reporter] All 13 Wild Boars are now safe!
[all cheering, screaming]
[shouting, cheering]
-[all cheering]
-[choir singing in Thai]
[no audible dialogue]
[music continues]
[gentle piano music playing]
[kicks ball]
♪ You're not alone, together we stand ♪
♪ I'll be by your side
You know I'll take your hand ♪
♪ When it gets cold
And it feels like the end ♪
♪ There's no place to go
You know I won't give in ♪
♪ No, I won't give in ♪
♪ Keep holding on ♪
♪ 'Cause you know we'll make it through ♪
♪ Just stay strong ♪
♪ 'Cause you know I'm here for you ♪
♪ There's nothing you can say
Nothing you can do ♪
♪ No other way
When it comes to the truth ♪
♪ So keep holding on ♪
♪ 'Cause you know we'll make it through… ♪
[Wild Boars yelling]
♪ So far away, I wish you were here ♪
♪ Before it's too late
This could all disappear ♪
♪ Before the doors close
And it comes to an end ♪
♪ With you by my side
I will fight and defend ♪
♪ I'll fight and defend… ♪
[Wild Boars shouting, laughing]
♪ Keep holding on ♪
♪ 'Cause you know we'll make it through ♪
♪ Just stay strong ♪
♪ 'Cause you know I'm here for you ♪
♪ There's nothing you can say
Nothing you can do ♪
♪ There's no other way
When it comes to the truth ♪
♪ So keep holding on ♪
♪ 'Cause you know we'll make it through ♪
♪ Keep holding on ♪
♪ 'Cause you know we'll make it through ♪
♪ Just stay strong ♪
♪ 'Cause you know I'm here for you ♪
♪ There's nothing you can say
Nothing you can do ♪
♪ There's no other way
When it comes to the truth ♪
♪ So keep holding on ♪
♪ 'Cause you know we'll make it through ♪
♪ Keep holding on ♪
♪ Just stay strong ♪
♪ Keep holding on ♪
♪ Just stay strong ♪
♪ Keep holding on ♪
[music fades out]
[Eak] They say if you look carefully
at the shape of the mountains,
you can see the sleeping princess.
It reminds us
that the first duty to family
is love.
I hope you'll always
be there for one another.
[ethereal music playing]
SHRINE OF CHAO MAE NANG NON