[dramatic music playing]
[thunder rumbling]
[reporter 1] The eyes of the world
are on Northern Thailand today
as efforts to extract the 12 boys
and their coach begin in earnest.
[reporter 2] The international team
will gather outside
of the Chiavari mountains.
[reporter speaking Japanese]
Come on! Let's go!
[reporter speaking German]
[reporter speaking in Mandarin]
All good down here!
[Thai reporter] Our sources have confirmed
that the cave's conditions
are more dangerous than ever.
[siren wailing on TV]
[people chanting]
[sirens wailing]
[suspenseful music playing]
[bubbling, splashing]
[boy] I'm scared I'll drown.
[man] I can't guarantee you'll make it.
But the water is rising.
I can guarantee
you'll die if you stay here.
Come on, Titan. Time to go.
Just think of home.
[cell phone ringing]
DAD CALLING
[ringing stops]
[man yawns]
[man] How'd you sleep, Titan?
[Titan] I always sleep better here.
It's 'cause no one's yelling all the time.
You have everything?
[Titan] Uh-huh. I have my shin guards,
my bike, everything.
I'm good to go.
Flashlight? For the hike
to Pla Cave after the game.
[sighs] I forgot. Damn.
[Titan groans]
Don't worry. We'll drop by your house
before going to the soccer field.
Don't worry about it, Coach.
I'll get one from a friend. It's okay.
I just wanna relax for one day.
Without my parents fighting all the time.
Please, Eak?
'Kay.
Eat it all.
But I'm not hungry yet.
If you don't eat,
how you gonna score against the big kids?
[Titan] That's a no-brainer.
I don't have to play harder.
I just have to play the ball smarter,
you know. The way Jay Chanathip does.
People underestimate that guy
because he's small too,
but he's really agile like Messi.
-Maybe even better.
-[chuckles]
Well, Messi Jay. If you're not gonna
eat that, put it in the box.
Even the smartest player in the world
needs energy for the ride to Pla Cave.
-And remember to change your clothes.
-Yes, sir! I'm on it.
[uplifting music playing]
[Titan commentating]
He's advancing forward.
Whoa! He's so good at dodging.
Uh-oh, is this Messi
or could this be Titan?
He dribbles down the field.
And there's the goal.
And now he's about to score!
[woman] Know what you want?
[Eak] Titan!
[loudspeaker] Those of you
who are not Thai citizens…
[guard 1] It's this kid again.
You keep crossing
back and forth by yourself.
-[guard 2] Maybe he's running drugs.
-Yeah, right.
Hey, kid.
Where the heck are your parents?
Do they know where you go every day?
-I know how to handle myself.
-[guard 1 scoffs] Oh really?
[Eak] Morning, sir.
[loudspeaker] Those of you
who are not Thai citizens,
please have your documents ready.
[guard 1] You're not a Thai citizen.
Hold on.
Eakaphon Chanthawong.
-[Eak] Yes.
-How's it written?
-It's E-A--
-Why do you ask that every day?
You know Coach has the pass.
[Eak] Titan, stop.
-So are you a soccer coach?
-[Titan] He--
I'm assistant
to Coach Nopparat Kanthawong.
-What's the team called?
-Wild Boars.
It's right here.
Maybe you should be
Unruly Pigs. [chuckles]
Come on!
Aren't you tired of being a big jerk?
Hey! Aren't you tired
of being a little jerk? How 'bout that?
-Nope. Not at all.
-Beat it.
-Keep left, Titan.
-[Titan] Okay.
[pleasant music playing]
[dramatic orchestral music plays]
-[computer beeps]
-Something's wrong.
You guys,
the Himawari-8 satellite is down.
The Japanese say they're working on it,
but it looks like
it's gonna take 15 hours.
-[man 1 groans]
-[man 2] Wow, 15 hours.
We should clock out early.
Wanna get a beer, man?
-[man 2] It's a deal.
-A storm system's coming in from Myanmar…
-[man 1] Noon, come on!
-…it's impossible to see 'cause--
The satellite's down. We heard.
Uh-huh. We have to tell Odd about it.
Hey, hey, hey.
Believe me, he'll probably go,
"Thai people don't listen
to weather news."
"They're wise enough to know
the weather changes every day."
[chuckles] No, he'll probably go, uh,
"I'll believe it's raining
when my clothes are wet."
-Cut it out, you guys!
-[men laughing]
Hey!
He's responsible for this place.
I'm gonna tell him now.
["Plastic Rose" by Maroon 5 playing]
[sings along to "Plastic Rose"]
[girl mocking his singing]
Get out, Jane! Get outta my face!
-Mom! Dom hit me with a towel!
-Jane, wait!
Oh, be quiet, both of you.
I don't want you disturbing your father.
Are you okay?
How come you took so long in the shower?
[sighs] Now, then. I've gotta get going
to open the shop this morning.
[Dom] Hey, Aunt Noi,
since Dad's not working,
he could watch my game, huh?
Your father's just out of the hospital.
His doctor says
all he should do is rest up.
Then, you and Uncle Toom
can see me play, right?
Just this once, please?
[Aunt Noi groans in frustration]
Just for the sake of argument,
if we were to close the shop
to watch your match…
Get up, hon.
…how on Earth would we be able
to get the money to pay
for all that hair gel you use, hmm?
It's not cheap, you know.
Okay, it's time to go.
Come on, Dom. Hurry up!
Let's go, Jane.
[boy] I'm not going.
I've got all my friends here.
Oh, in Chiang Mai,
you'll make new friends.
Your cousin will introduce you.
But, Grandma, it won't be the same.
You'll get used to it,
eventually. Don't worry.
[boy] When Tee moves up to the Under 17s,
Biw and I will be team captains.
Huh. It's different for Biw, dear.
His family has plenty of money.
Believe me,
you will be better off with Uncle Chai.
Tonight, when you get home,
we will call him with the good news.
I don't wanna go.
Enough of that. All the men
who live in this house have had bad luck.
I swear,
I won't let that happen to you, ever.
-Be home by 6:00, okay?
-[phone beeping]
[cell phone beeps]
-[traditional Thai music playing]
-[cell phone ringing]
[cell phone continues ringing]
Yeah? What is it?
[Phong] Are you still in bed?
Uh, I'm ready!
[Phong] Ready, my ass!
Ghosts aren't afraid of pillows.
Well, they didn't get me last night.
-[Phong] Come on and pick me up!
-Why are you getting so worked up?
[Phong] Because you're always late,
that's why.
Come on,
we have to stop by the church too.
-[band playing "Nearer, My God, to Thee"]
-♪ Nearer, my God, to Thee ♪
♪ Nearer to Thee ♪
♪ E'en though it is a cross… ♪
[motorbike revving]
♪ That raiseth me… ♪
Adul, you need to find the tempo.
Adul, you're dragging!
[band continues playing]
All right, you can go join your friends.
[motorbike revs loudly]
[singing continues]
Thank you very much, Pastor.
[suspenseful music playing]
[floorboard creaks]
-[woman] Where are you going, Mark?
-Coach Eak wants me at practice.
[woman] Why don't you eat first
before you go?
[Mark] I'm not very hungry right now.
Now, here's some money for lunch,
and keep some for dinner too.
-Okay.
-How come you look so skinny?
People will think I don't take
good care of you. We can't have that, huh?
No one thinks I'm skinny.
Why do you say that?
[woman] Hey, if I don't look after you,
then who will, huh?
[Titan shouting] Hey, Mark! Let's go!
[Mark] Okay. Be right there!
Come on! We're in a hurry.
[woman] Mark,
if you're thirsty, drink water.
-[Mark] Okay.
-[Titan] Let's get going!
-[woman] Hi, Eak.
-[Eak] Good morning.
-Mark.
-[Mark] Bye, Mom. See you later.
[bike bell chimes]
[uplifting music playing]
[boy] Come to Pla Cave with us.
It'll be fun.
Ah, forget it.
[boy] You never do anything with the team.
I play soccer with them all.
[boy] You never do anything else with us.
You only play soccer.
-[Mix] Hey, that's my juice!
-[boy] Ugh!
-What the hell! That's my juice!
-Nobody drinks durian juice. Are you nuts?
Well, I do.
I can't believe
you asked me to hold it for you.
-I'm not going to the cave.
-Wow! What a coward.
My dad's friend
was trapped in a cave for three hours.
He was never the same again.
My dad would kill me if I went.
And I have a lot of life left to live.
It's the same
for the rest of us, you dick.
-Just come to the cave with us.
-[Mix] All right.
-You can't break your word.
-[Mix] Uh-huh.
[boy] You know I can't-- Ow!
He did it!
I'm sorry, Tee!
Be careful, guys.
The ball almost hit Mali.
Mali.
-I can't bail on the guys.
-That's all you ever say.
The small ones are scared of ghosts.
What kind of captain would I be
if I didn't scare them shitless?
-Okay?
-Look! They're coming.
I-- I'll call you tonight.
-Good morning, Coach Eak.
-Hey, Tee.
That's funny!
-I thought your girlfriend had pink hair.
-[Tee] Shut up!
-Make sure you scare this one the worst.
-[Tee] You got it.
-[Titan groans]
-Hey! Cut that out!
[Titan laughs]
[Tee] All right, everyone!
Start warming up! Let's go!
-[Adul] Come on! Let's go!
-Note, get up! Note! Let's go!
[Note] Hey, Biw! Wait for me!
[Eak] One, two, three…
-I'm sorry, I forgot the time.
-We'll make up for it.
-We're running behind.
-[Tee] Okay.
-What happened to Night?
-[Tee] Uh…
[Note] Night?
He went to make merit at the temple
for his birthday. He's coming now.
Hey, there he is now!
[all] ♪ Happy, happy birthday
Happy, happy birthday ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you, to you
Happy birthday to you, to you ♪
[Tee] ♪ Happy birthday
Peeraphat Somphiangchai ♪
[all] ♪ To you, to you! ♪
[boys laughing]
[Eak] Night, do your best
on the big team next year.
-[Night] Thanks.
-You guys, continue with your warm-ups.
-[boys] Okay, coach.
-[Eak] Slackers.
Hey, Coach.
These are my cousins. Nick and Tle.
-[both] Hi.
-[Eak] Welcome. Wanna join the Wild Boars?
-[Tle] Yeah.
-[Nick] Uh-huh.
I told them if they played on the team,
you'd let them come to Pla Cave with us.
-They're packed and ready.
-[Eak laughs] Okay.
Leave the cave part out
when you meet Coach Nop.
It'll make him happy if he thinks you
wanna play because you love soccer, okay?
-[boys] Yeah.
-Go and warm up.
-[Tle] Thank you, sir.
-[Tee] Thanks.
Go and get ready. And no slacking off!
[Night] Coach Eak's cool.
He's just like one of us.
[Tle] You're right.
[Eak] Wild Boars!
Let's go!
[crowd cheering on TV]
[football commentary on TV]
I can't believe how much you suck!
[knocking]
Sorry, Odd. But I think
we may have a problem up north.
Hey, Noon, would you mind moving over?
-Um…
-[Odd] Come on! Move over!
-I only--
-[Odd] Let me guess.
You don't usually
watch soccer matches, huh?
Uh, I played a lot
of sports back in school.
Come on!
The World Cup isn't school soccer. Oh!
Uh. Is that the Ministry of Agriculture
report I wanted from you? Hand it over.
-I'm actually still writing it.
-Why's that?
-[Noon] Because it's raining in Myanmar.
-[groans]
[laughing] So what?!
I would only worry if it snowed.
I think that we might be dealing
with a major storm that's rolling--
Stop it.
[patronizingly] Monsoon season
isn't due for a while.
-You don't get it. I'm sure that's not it.
-I get it.
I get exactly what you're doing.
But you're wrong.
You're an intern.
I'm the senior meteorologist.
Who do you think knows better? Just relax.
What a tragedy,
we get some rain after this drought.
-Isn't that a good thing, huh?
-[fans cheer on TV]
Hey! What?
Please. I wouldn't say anything
if this wasn't serious.
Twenty millimeters an hour,
and there's more on the way.
Look at the pressure changes
coming off the Indian Ocean.
This is Taunggyi,
where the report came in from an hour ago.
I calculated that it will be here
in less than two hours.
And it will be here in two more hours.
If we don't act, it'll be way too late.
And you want me to do what?
Issue an alert for Chiang Mai,
Chiang Rai, and Mae Hong Son provinces.
An alert based on this little…
Uh-uh. Forget about it.
Remember what happened last time? Oh!
Panicking! I got it wrong
and scared the hell out of six million,
and it was my ass they chewed out.
[Noon inhales and sighs]
Just finish that report for the Ministry
of Agriculture I asked for.
Come on now. Okay? Finish today.
So I can go home.
[football playing on TV]
All right.
[football fans cheering on TV]
No. Hey, Noon.
Don't forget the door. Hey, Noon!
NORTHERN THAILAND
CHIANG RAI PROVINCE
-[Titan] Got it!
-Seriously?
How come you grabbed our ball?
Huh? We're practicing.
Oh, come on! You know what?
Coach Eak probably matched me with you,
so you might learn something.
You understand? Hey, Mark.
-What's up?
-You think I could borrow your flashlight?
Titan, you leave us alone,
I'll give you my flashlight.
I've got an extra.
Score! [laughs]
[goalie] What do you need
a flashlight for?
[Titan] We're going to Pla Cave.
After we kick your butts, of course.
[goalie] Funny, but this is our home turf.
We're gonna be doing the butt-kicking.
And Pla Cave's closed anyway.
We went there last week.
-[Tee] Really?
-[goalie] Yeah.
That's good.
I guess I'll take Mali out after all.
She wanted me
to meet some of her friends later.
Wait. You're buying this?
The sign said it's closed until next year.
If you don't believe me,
go check it out yourself. Moron.
-Hey, Titan. Hey! Hey! Titan!
-[goalie] What?
[Eak] Good. Energy.
Energy, guys!
Nice. Use your other foot, Phong.
Phong!
Am I not loud enough for you?
[laughs] I heard you.
My way's just easier.
Phong!
You wanna play on this team, don't you?
Then why don't you start
listening to Coach Eak?
You set back up
and do it the way you were told, okay?
[football whistle toots]
[Nop] Look.
I know you care
about every one of those boys.
They're like the little brothers
I never had.
[Nop] Well,
they don't need brothers.
They've got each other for that.
You have to be more than that.
Shape them and guide them.
Make the tough calls
when no one else will.
Being their brother on its own
just isn't enough.
When your father died,
you needed someone
to take his place, didn't you?
The abbot was a father figure to you
at the monastery.
Now you can pass it on
by doing the same for those boys.
Got it?
Anyway, I've gotta go.
I've got my daughter's recital.
You'll be just fine.
I'm not gonna let you down.
I'm not the one
you're gonna lose sleep over.
Excuse me. This way, Governor.
-All right, yes.
-Follow me.
Am I being forced to transfer?
We've known one another for years.
I'll be completely honest with you.
They asked for honest and reliable.
Somebody like you.
To help out in Phayao.
Chiang Rai doesn't want reliable?
Huh?
Was moving all the way here
from Bangkok not enough for you?
Honestly, Phayao isn't even that far
from here to begin with.
Your daughters don't even
have to change schools.
You can see them on weekends.
Have fun. Shopping. Eat out.
Straightforward.
[Narongsak sighs]
[Kiattisak groans]
Don't complicate things now.
The ministry expects that you will bring
what you brought in Chiang Rai to Phayao.
If not even more.
That's all.
Don't overthink it.
[clicking, whirring]
You're kidding! Boss said forget it.
How come you're still trying?
Him not wanting paperwork
doesn't mean I'm gonna ignore it.
-People could be in trouble.
-[man 1] Mm. Mm.
We've gotta track
the weather up there in real time.
-How do we do that?
-[Noon sighs]
What did people used to do
before they had satellites?
Don't think they did
much of anything. [scoffs]
-Yeah.
-Dude. Hey, stop it.
You could drive up there yourself.
Right? I'm gonna drive 12 whole hours
to check out Myanmar's weather.
[man 2] Consider it a road trip.
-[man 1] Let's all go. [laughs]
-[man 2] Sure.
[sighs] It's impossible to think
with you two around.
[huffs]
[woman] Night!
Night, you forgot your water bottle.
-Thank you.
-Go on. Take a drink. Come on.
So what kind of birthday cake
did you want for tonight?
You choose whatever.
[Mom] If you let me choose the cake,
then you're getting SpongeBob
this time too.
Oh, please tell me you're joking?
Mom, I'm not a little kid.
Once we're done, I'm gonna come home early
to help you set up.
Weren't you going somewhere
with your friends?
[Night] We were going to go to Pla Cave.
It's apparently closed, though.
Either way, you can still hang out. Hmm?
It's your day.
[clicks tongue] Have fun.
You're aging off the team.
You won't see them much anymore.
[Mom] Yes, it's your last year
on the team.
So go have fun with them while you can.
I'll take care of everything. Come on!
Have fun, Son! See you!
[woman] Titan!
-[man] Hey, Son!
-[woman] Mom's over here, Titan!
Titan!
-[Eak] Assemble, everyone!
-[football whistle blows]
[Eak] Hurry up.
Come on, Titan.
Red, you're kicking off.
On the bench, Nick and Tle first.
-[both] Sure.
-Note, goalkeeper.
Boon-Nam, grab a jersey.
You're playing with blue today.
Wait a minute. Why me?
Well, each team has 13 players.
That's double unlucky.
So that means we need to share our luck
with the other team.
We clear? Yut, goalkeeping blue today.
-Sure.
-Okay. Tee?
-Yeah?
-Come on.
One, two, three!
[all] Wild Boars! Hey!
-[Tee] Let's do this!
-[boys shout excitedly]
-[Titan] I don't wanna do this.
-[Eak] Titan.
What's wrong?
[Titan] Pla Cave's closed.
Well, it's not the end of the world.
[shouts] Yes, it is!
[pensive music playing]
[football whistle blows]
[boys shouting, chattering]
[blows whistle]
[Tle] Pla Cave's not open.
You know what?
Tham Luang Cave is. Come on!
-[Note] What do you think?
-[Mix] We should go. Come on.
-[Note] Let's go. Let's do it.
-Really?
-[all] Yeah!
-He's relaxed enough. He should study now.
He's doing fine.
Just let him go have fun with his friends.
[Dad] He's falling behind in school.
Where'd you spend the night?
It doesn't matter!
Please, Tai. It does.
You always let him stay at Eak's house,
instead of home.
Hey, without him, we wouldn't
have even known they had a game.
You mean he's the one who told you?
[Dad] We're Titan's parents. Not Eak.
He goes over to Eak's place
because of you!
He's our responsibility.
We have to take care of him.
[Tai] He's desperate for a father figure
'cause you're a terrible--
Okay. We better get going.
[boys cheering]
-[Eak] Tee.
-[Tee] Yes?
-[Eak] You're at the end.
-[Tee] Yes, sir!
-[Eak] Not far.
-[Note] Come on. Go!
[all talking excitedly]
[Eak] Don't use your front brake
while you're going downhill.
[boys talking excitedly]
[Phong] Whoo! Come on! Let's go!
Hey, Boon-Nam. Where you going?
[boy shouting]
[Boon-Nam] I can't go with you guys.
My mom told me to come home.
You listen to her now?
[Boon-Nam] Yeah. But she said
she'd make me cookies if I head home now.
Have fun with everyone.
I gotta go.
[gentle music playing]
[Tee] Mix!
Can't back out now. Come on!
[serene music playing]
-[boy laughing]
-[Note] Let's go!
-[Phong] Let's go, yeah!
-Whoo-hoo!
-[Phong] Let's go, come on!
-[blows a kiss]
Whoo-hoo! Chill!
Yeah! Come on!
-[Tle] Let's go!
-[Phong] Look at the camera, Eak.
[laughs] Come on!
Titan! Titan! Titan!
Look at the camera!
-What's wrong?
-[Biw] Come on, wait for me!
[Phong] Titan, smile.
[Phong whooping] Wait for us!
[thunder rumbles]
[Noon] Thirty millimeters? Are you sure?
[man] Yeah.
And it's not stopping anytime soon.
[Noon] I'll call you back
in a half an hour.
And thank you.
Hey, guys. Listen up.
[man 1] What's up?
My roommate's ex-boyfriend's uncle
lives out in Pha Mee.
[man 2] Okay.
It's on the border
between Myanmar and Thailand.
-[man 2 scoffs] How do you know that?
-[scoffs] A map! Ever heard of it?
Come on, Noon. Would you just relax?
I was on the phone with him just now.
They said they got 30 millimeters of rain.
[man 1] Huh?
[man 2 gasps softly]
If it keeps going at this rate…
Man.
You better be sure about this.
There's no second chance for us
if we get fired for this.
[man 1] Yeah.
Well, then. Call anyone else
you can think of who's living up there.
Do it now.
Maybe your ex-girlfriend's weird uncle.
The one who's related to your aunt?
-The one--
-[Noon grunts]
Just joking.
[thunder rumbles in distance]
[Note] All right, all right!
We're heading to the cave! [whoops]
[poignant music playing]
[Note] Come on, guys!
[Tee] Come on! Come on! Hurry up!
Let's go!
[boys laughing]
[boys talking excitedly]
[boys shouting and laughing]
[foreboding music playing]
[Eak] We won't be in there for long.
I'm gonna bring my backpack.
If you don't wanna carry yours,
then leave it.
-Come on.
-[Tee] Yes, Coach.
We'll be back soon anyway.
[Eak clears his throat]
Coach, I can't stay.
I already told you about that.
Titan,
we'll be right back.
An hour tops
and you'll be home in time for tutoring.
You're not gonna say sorry to me?
You knew I didn't want my parents
to come to the game.
Why did you have to invite them?
[Eak sighs]
Okay.
I'm not gonna apologize.
They wanted to know you were safe,
so I told them where you'd be.
-They came on their own.
-Okay, whatever. It's still 'cause of you!
You know how my parents are!
[Eak sighs]
[Eak] Come here.
Got something to show you.
Boys!
Come on.
[tense string music playing]
[Mix] Titan, let's go.
[sacred music playing]
Hey, Note. Who's Chao Mae Nang Non?
[Note] That's the name
of the vengeful princess
whose spirit still lives in the cave.
-[Tle] Oh shit. Why's she vengeful?
-[Note] I don't know.
[Eak sighs]
The myth goes that there was a princess
who fell for a stable boy.
She got pregnant.
Her father, the king,
found out about their relationship.
He was furious
and wanted the stable boy dead.
So they ran.
They were cornered up in these mountains.
The stable boy
was slaughtered in front of her.
She was devastated.
So she hid in a cave.
Took a pin to her throat
and committed suicide.
[Note] Crazy.
They say if you look carefully,
you can see her
in the shape of the mountains.
It's a reminder.
A reminder of pain
that the king was cursed with,
so he would never forget
that the duty you have to your family
is to love.
We get to choose our family as well.
Like her.
She chose to love that boy
until the very end. Right?
Her story didn't end well,
but it can for this whole team.
You guys are really lucky.
You get to decide
what you think about your family.
By your age, I was already an orphan.
I didn't have anybody.
Taught me to cast a wide net.
To catch somebody.
I hope you will all be there
for each other,
like a family.
And I
will be here for you
as much as I can be.
I mean it, guys.
Even if you don't understand my methods.
Here. Long way to go.
It's prettier inside.
Thank you, Coach!
[Note] I'll lead you inside.
[Titan] Let's go!
[boy shouting excitedly]
[yawns]
[man] Here's your dinner.
[thunder rumbling]
[ominous music playing]
[phone ringing]
National Park Office.
Yes. Hello. This is a check-in
from the TMD in Bangkok.
Do you see any clouds?
[sighs] Mm, okay.
It's been a very long day.
I still have to do paperwork,
so if this isn't an emergency--
I just need a minute.
Are there any clouds in the sky?
-Probably. That's where they always are.
-I mean rain clouds. Do you see any?
[sighs impatiently] Hold on.
[sighs softly]
-[disquieting music playing]
-How bad did you say it is?
I didn't. But at Tachiliek and Pha Mee,
we got reports of 30 millimeters an hour.
[disquieting music playing]
[boys gasping, chattering excitedly]
[Eak] You're being too loud. Follow me.
[disquieting music plays]
[Pim] Pha Mee
is only a few miles away from here.
It's coming right for us.
Everyone here's gone home already.
[Noon] Could you please
measure the rainfall?
Could I what?
The monsoon might be here
earlier than we thought.
Look, this isn't some kind of joke.
You need to issue an alert, and I need it
to authorize closing the park.
[Noon] I can't. I'm just an intern.
But I need your help with something.
If it starts to rain, would you
report the measurements back to me?
Then I can bring it to my boss
and ask him to issue an alert.
If you're right
about 30 millimeters per hour,
then that means
you've got no time to spare.
You've gotta act immediately.
People are at risk the longer you wait.
I can close the parks and caves,
but without an alert
that won't mean anything.
Do you understand?
Yeah.
KHUN NAM NATIONAL FOREST
[Noon] Odd! Wait a minute!
What? What now?
Belgium and Tunisia are playing.
I need to get home--
We don't have time for that!
Pha Mee is getting
30 millimeters of rain per hour.
And rain clouds in Khun Nam
are rolling in at an alarming rate.
[Odd] Okay.
[Noon] Pha Mee, Khun Nam, and Chiang Rai.
We can't afford to wait around here.
Okay.
Chiang Rai, Chiang Mai,
and Mae Hong Son, but that's it.
It's up to the senior provincial officers
to decide whether or not
they want to issue an alert.
Okay?
And just remember,
put your signature down
to verify the paperwork.
If anything goes south,
you'll be responsible.
Understand?
Interns must be pretty easy to blame,
aren't we?
[thunder rumbling]
[clicking, whirring]
[keys tapping vigorously]
[thunder rumbling]
[cell phone beeps]
SEVERE STORM WARNING
-Argh! [laughs]
-[Biw screams]
[Biw] You'd scream too
if I grabbed your leg in the dark--
-[Phong] Look! Who's that?
-Argh!
-[Biw screams]
-[Phong] Dom!
[Tee laughing]
[Tee] Wait for me! Damn it, Dom.
[Biw] Run! Let's run from the ghost!
[boys chatting]
Oh wow!
-[Dom] It's beautiful.
-[Note] Awesome.
What's that?
I've never seen anything like it.
[boy 1] Wow.
-[boy 2] Look at that.
-[boy 3] So cool.
-[Mark] Look over there!
-[Biw] It's so pretty.
-[Dom] It looks just like a starry sky.
-[Phong] Wow!
-That's gorgeous
-You're right.
Maybe. But it's not as nice
as the real sky.
[Note] Wow.
Hey! Joking.
[all laughing]
-[alarm beeping]
-[boys laughing]
Coach, it's four o'clock.
Hey, Coach.
Can we stay for five more minutes?
Solid try.
Come on, then. Tee, time to go back.
Let's come back again.
[Eak] Next time for sure.
-[Mix] I wanna be in the middle.
-[Dom] I'll guard the back.
-[Titan] What a show-off.
-[Eak] Anyone else over there?
[Adul] May God show us the way.
No.
[Tee] Coach Eak!
I think we have a problem!
[Dom] What's wrong?
[Titan] What is it?
[Eak] Walk carefully.
[foreboding music playing]
[dialing]
[thunder rumbling]
[cell phone ringing]
Hello? What is it?
No, I haven't seen Phong.
Biw was gonna pick him up
this morning from what I know.
Well,
I'll give you a call back when I can.
[foreboding music playing]
THAM LUANG ENTRANCE
[Night's mom] I'm really sorry
to keep you waiting.
Usually, Night doesn't stay out this late.
[man] I'm sure he's fine.
Don't worry. He'll be here.
-[Nop] Boon-Nam. Where is everyone?
-[Boon-Nam] Hi.
[Night's mom] Come in quick.
You're soaked.
You didn't go with the others
after the game?
No, I didn't.
My mom was baking cookies today.
So I didn't wanna go to Tham Luang Cave.
[Night's mom] Huh?
Boon-Nam. Boon-Nam. Boon-Nam.
Who went to Tham Luang?
Eak did. With the whole team.
Yeah, Coach. They all went there together
after the game. Why?
[Nop] When was the last time
you saw or heard from Night?
-[Night's dad] At the game this morning.
-[Night's mom] Yeah, the game.
Call him right now, okay?
-[Night's dad] Call Night.
-Do it right now!
Boon-Nam, try to call all the boys.
Tell me if you reach anyone.
I'm calling Eak.
[yelling] Eak! Eak! Can you hear me?
Who's there?
The cave is flooded!
There's no way in! And no way out!
Dear!
[Night's dad]
Is one of these Night's bike?
Hello.
[gasps]
Oh!
[groans]
[dull thud]
[cell phone ringing]
-Hello.
-[man] Hello, Governor.
We're calling to report there may be
several kids trapped in Tham Luang Cave.
How many?
[Pim] This is the only entry point.
[Nop] Are you sure?
[distant voices shouting]
[Titan's mom] Titan!
[woman] Hurry up!
[Night's mom] Night, where are you?
[man] Son! Where are you?
Nop! Where is he? Let me see my son now!
[Nop] No, no, no, no, no. Hold on!
You can't go in there. It's dangerous.
I already tried!
And so did the rangers.
[women crying]
The current pushed us out.
There's no way through.
-[Titan's dad] Where is Eak?
-[Nop] In there with the others.
Please calm down.
We've called the local authorities.
Why didn't you close the cave, huh?
This is your fault!
[sobbing] Night's birthday party
was tonight.
There's no way they might drown, right?
How can they survive in there?
[crying] How do we get them home?
[climactic music plays]
[monks chanting]