[tense music playing]
[Tee] Hey, Biw.
Should I be worried about you?
Just hold on.
-[urinating]
-[Tee chuckles]
[laughs]
What's going on?
Biw is taking
the longest pee in existence.
-Hey!
-[pebble clatters]
-[Eak laughs]
-[Biw] I have to get permission first.
I don't want the princess
to get even more angry.
[Eak] Baitoey's serving breakfast.
[Biw] Let's go, Tee.
[Tee] Hey, wait for me. Biw, wait.
[Tee] Aren't you hungry?
Not right now.
I'd rather pray while it's quiet.
You better hurry,
before Titan eats all the food.
[foreboding music playing]
-[Eak] Hey. Hey.
-Hm?
The SEALs are back.
-Really?
-Yeah.
That's good. Finally. Let's go.
[Aran] They found a way
to hold back the water from coming in.
We can do daily supply runs now.
-That's great.
-[men chatting]
I haven't been able
to get the coach to eat anything.
I didn't know what to say.
When he saw how low we were on food,
he insisted we give his share to the boys.
These are letters to the boys' families.
And a message for the governor.
It's critical.
Okay.
Hey, Aran.
What's the, uh, plan
to get the boys out of here?
[unsettling music playing]
Unfortunately, our worst scenario
is now our best option.
We have reviewed the alternatives,
including inflating a flexible tunnel,
and we have concluded
that teaching these boys to scuba dive
is the most realistic option.
I have asked Major Hensen and his team
to put together a course-of-action plan.
-Major.
-Thank you, Admiral.
We've broken this operation down
into a series of manageable chunks
so we can approach
the problem step by step.
How long will it take?
It's hard to say right now.
We're already gathering gear.
We've put out a call for more tanks.
We need 600 to complete the mission.
We have 200 on site,
plus a promise of another 200.
That leaves us 200 short.
And we still have to prep the cave
to have enough oxygen for the boys
and their divers to swim out.
We're gonna have to pre-stage tanks
in each of the chambers between the sumps.
They'll change tanks as they come out.
Not to mention
teach 13 half-starved young men
how to scuba dive through some
of the ugliest conditions I've ever seen.
[John] That is not something
that can happen overnight.
You must have some idea of a time frame.
-Three weeks, minimum.
-Possibly four.
[Chet] Governor.
From Dr. Pak.
He says the boys
are running out of oxygen.
He was worried this would happen.
Normally, the air we breathe
is around 21% oxygen by volume.
Anything below 19.5%
is considered oxygen-deficient.
Now, once you get below 15%,
you're at risk for developing hypoxia.
Which means diminished mental capacity,
lowered heart rates, loss of coordination,
and eventually death.
The doctor says
the chamber is at 16% oxygen.
Chet, what does it mean for us?
[Chet sighs]
Well, based on the levels we measured
on our first run of supplies,
we estimate the chamber
will drop below 15% in less than a week.
So we finally get the water levels down,
find a way to keep them fed,
and now they may suffocate.
[tense music playing]
It's settled, then.
You must speed up our rescue timeline.
You don't get four weeks, or three.
You have one.
Only one.
[theme music playing]
[birds singing]
[tranquil music playing]
[muffled] Faster!
Oh! [laughing]
-Ah!
-Why'd you stop?
[woman sighs, pants]
I can't believe you call this fun.
-[woman pants]
-Wait till it's race day.
With a little luck,
all of your work will pay off.
[laughs]
-Yeah. Can't wait.
-[exhales]
Huh?
Ah.
It's a lucky coin.
[soothing music playing]
[Meow] Hold on. What are you doing?
I'm making a wish.
What about Omsin, huh?
Who?
The sea turtle who died
after swallowing 915 coins.
So much suffering.
I hate the thought of someone suffering
for good fortune. [scoffs]
You know?
I love that about you.
Mm.
Yeah.
If we've trained hard enough to win,
then we'll win no matter what.
Easy-peasy. No luck needed.
-Hmm.
-[phone ringing]
Didn't you once say
I was lucky just to have you?
[grunts with frustration]
Oh my!
[phone continues ringing]
Navy SEALs never quit,
even retired ones.
[ringing stops]
Hey, Chet.
[Chet] Hey, Sam. Can we talk?
Yeah. What's going on? What is it?
[Chet] We don't have enough oxygen tanks
here at Tham Luang.
Can you please help us
find some and bring them here?
Sure. I can do that.
[Chet] That's my man!
I'll send the details through Line.
[soothing music playing]
So, he wants you to go?
I'm not going anywhere.
Besides, we have a race on Sunday.
Hmm?
Okay.
Chet told me they need more oxygen.
He asked if I could find some more
and have them sent up to Tham Luang.
Hmm.
Well, I'm not complaining
about this, you know?
[Sam chuckles]
[Kelly] The pumps are working
better than I hoped.
Almost too well.
We're expelling
1.6 million liters per hour.
At that rate, is it possible
to drain the cave completely?
So we can get the water low enough
to get more air in?
No.
Especially not with this rain
still coming down.
But I'm confident that we can keep
the water level safe for divers
as long as we need to.
The problem is…
The problem is
we're hours away from running out
of places to dump the water.
[Pim] There aren't many options
in this area.
Especially because the ground
is already oversaturated from the rain.
So where does that leave us?
[foreboding music playing]
We can flood this farmland.
It's in Mae Sai.
There's more than enough space to hold
the amount of water we're anticipating.
But we'll destroy all their crops.
It'll be a huge sacrifice for them.
We have two enemies right now.
Weather and water.
One of those, we cannot control.
Go. Talk to the farmers.
-[thunder rumbles]
-[disquieting music playing]
[Sam] If you hadn't given him CPR,
he would've died.
[man] His mouth was green
when he came up.
-[Sam] Didn't even leave the navy.
-[man laughs] I gotta give it to him.
-[man] He's really something.
-[Sam] We've arrived.
-Hey, hey!
-[Sam] Finally!
-There's the man!
-[Sam laughing]
-[Chet laughs]
-[Sam] Chet, my man!
Hey, you let Buddy tag along?
He wanted to come along.
[Chet laughs]
[Chet] Come take these tanks.
You guys, Sam was my mentor.
He's legendary and tough.
He's in better shape in retirement
than most of you are right now.
Leave me alone, Chet.
-Leave them alone too.
-[Chet] Ah, come on!
How about we put 'em
in a pool full of ice, huh?
Like you did with me.
-[Chet laughs] Legendary.
-All right, guys. Let's go!
[Chet laughs]
[loudspeaker announcement in Thai]
What does Tee look like?
He's tall.
-Okay. Tall.
-[man] Pink!
-[Pink] Yeah.
-Pink. You can't run off like that.
I have to know where you are.
But he's going to see Tee
and deliver a message for me.
Tell Tee, if he ever gets trapped
in a cave again, I'll kill him!
Okay, I will.
I'll deliver the message for you.
[Pink] Okay.
So Tee is your son, then?
He is. Are you going to see him now?
[Aran] Yes.
Please tell our son
that we love him very much.
[man] Tell him not to worry.
Just take care of himself.
I will.
[softly] Okay.
See you.
[Note] I see something moving
under the water.
[dramatic musical flourish]
I'm serious.
Did you see that?
It's humungous. It's gigantic.
What if
it's the water dragon?
-[screaming]
-[yells in fright]
[mock yelling]
-Dude! Not cool.
-[laughing]
[boys shout]
Morning, Wild Boars. Oh.
[Rick] How many of you can swim?
[Aran] Adul, did your friends
get what he said?
He wants to know if we can swim.
[all boys] I can! Me too!
And have any of you
ever been scuba diving?
He's asking if we can scuba dive.
[boys murmur]
Okay. I'd say today is your lucky day.
Today, you officially start
SEAL Dive Training boot camp.
Whoa!
So awesome!
Does that mean
we're going to dive out of here?
Yes.
-We're diving?
-Hey, guys.
They wouldn't ask
if they thought it was hard for us.
[boy] Yeah, I agree with Tee.
That's right.
So let's get started.
These two, Rick and John,
are gonna start fitting you guys
for your scuba gear.
Then we'll jump in, okay?
-All right.
-Okay.
Ready, guys?
-[Aran] Great.
-All right.
[all boys] Thank you, Teacher.
Okay, so this is a mask.
It goes on your face like this.
-You try.
-Uh, he means me? All right.
This is called a regulator.
It goes in your mouth.
Remember, don't bite.
-[Aran] Mm?
-[Tee] Mm.
You attach the oxygen tank here.
First, you put it over the tank like this.
Then, you pull the strap
until it makes a locking sound.
[Aran] Okay, try it.
Keep in mind, don't bite. Okay?
-Okay, yeah.
-[Aran] Good.
Go.
Hey! Hey, Titan!
-[Eak laughs]
-[laughing] Hey!
[playful music playing]
-Good?
-Good work. Doing good.
[boys laughing]
You can adjust them.
Good? Oh!
[boys] Mark! Mark!
[John] You all right? Yeah.
[boys laughing]
[laughter continues]
[laughing]
[Sam] It's incredible, Meow.
People are showing up from everywhere.
It's not just rescue workers here.
Here. I'll show you.
Barbers are giving free haircuts, see?
Massages in this tent.
Free massages for anyone.
You can have your laundry done here.
[chuckles] It's crazy.
Here are some donated items.
Rain boots, jackets,
toothpaste, toothbrushes. All free.
Can you believe this?
So many people have come here,
willing to drop everything
to help these boys.
Wow! Those people are really incredible
for helping out.
[train announcement in Thai]
-Honey, I'm almost at work now.
-[Sam] I see.
Don't let Chet
work you too hard, okay, honey?
[Sam] I won't.
We're just filling oxygen tanks
and putting them in the cave.
Then I'll be on the next flight back.
-Easy-peasy.
-[Meow laughs]
Of course. Only you would say
it will be easy.
Return safely, okay?
Okay.
[Meow] All right. Bye for now.
[eerie music playing]
[thunder rumbles]
[man] My crop is just five weeks old.
If you flood my field,
the rice won't survive.
I understand your concerns, really.
And if there were another way
to manage the water,
we would do it, without question.
[man 2] I've been watching
what's been going on.
My heart breaks for the boys
and their families too.
But I have my own family
to take care of too.
[farmers murmur in agreement]
We understand.
We know we're asking a lot from you.
But if we don't do this,
then the cave will remain flooded.
The divers will be unable
to reach the boys.
And the boys
will never make it out of the cave.
[man 3] What about our paddies? Our lives?
[man 4] Yeah. How are we supposed
to live if our crops die?
You can flood my rice paddies.
[poignant music playing]
This country can easily grow more rice.
But we can't regrow the lives
of these young, innocent boys.
-[man] She's right.
-[man] I think I'm gonna sign.
[woman] Let's do as she said.
-[woman] We should all help out.
-[man] Okay, I'll sign.
-[man] We gotta get them out of there.
-[man] We gotta help them.
[woman] Let's all sign it then. Here.
[man] We'll sign right now.
[stirring music playing]
-[man] Everybody should sign.
-[woman] Let's help however we can.
[man] Let's do something!
-[farmers murmuring]
-[man] Hand it over here. I'll sign.
[man] We all need to sign. Everybody.
What if was your son? What would you do?
Come on. Sign it right now.
I'm willing. We need to save these boys.
We need two volunteers.
Good.
Coach, leading the way.
All right. Who else?
-I'll go.
-Come on.
-What's your name?
-It's Tee.
[boy] Well, if Tee is doing it,
then I will too.
Oh! Our famous team captain!
I met your little sister earlier.
She told me she misses you.
-That doesn't sound like her at all.
-[chuckles]
You're right, but you know,
your dad did tell me to tell you
not to worry about the family.
Focus on taking good care of yourself.
My dad is out there too?
Yes.
Okay, first lesson is the most important.
[speech fades]
Never hold your breath underwater.
You could pop your lungs
like a balloon if you do that, so…
[contemplative music playing]
[muffled] The most important thing to do
is to breathe normally, always.
[Aran] Here.
Ready, Tee?
[boys chattering]
[John] You good?
[John] And breathe.
[inhales and exhales]
[breathing evenly]
[muffled shout, breathing rapidly]
[muffled shout]
[Tee coughing] I can't take it anymore.
-[John] Come on out.
-[Aran] Okay.
-[Tee coughing]
-It's okay. That's enough for now.
There's a lot of equipment to get used to.
We will support you
until you can do it yourself.
Okay.
All right. Who's next, then?
[Pim] They all agreed.
Kelly.
This has to be done.
What if these farmers give up everything…
and it's still not enough?
[poignant music playing]
[Pim] We will train the boys to dive.
We will find a way.
[Pim] I'm headed back to camp.
Want a lift?
I've gotta get the pump crew started. Uh…
They can work through the night
to reroute the pipes.
I'll catch you tomorrow.
See you tomorrow.
[rescue crew chatting]
So, how are you two old-timers
holding up with the work?
-Can't break us, Chet.
-[Chet chuckles]
If you're up for it,
I'd love to give the new guys a break.
They've been going nonstop.
[man shouts instructions in Thai]
What do you say?
Hooyah!
-Of course. Let's go.
-[Chet] Okay, then.
You'll drop your tanks
at chamber number six.
Okay, follow me.
A guide rope will lead you straight there.
And whatever you do,
do not let go of the rope.
There's almost zero visibility.
Pace yourself. Don't rush.
You'll see a green guide rope
on the way out.
Why green?
When you hit green,
you only have 20 meters left to go.
But be warned.
This isn't Phuket. Not by any means.
-Oh.
-You'll get some bruises.
-[diver grunts]
-[Sam] Hey!
[Buddy] Oh, hey.
It's okay. Just breathe.
Okay.
[Chet] It's going to be okay.
-Hold on. Okay, up.
-[diver grunts]
-One, two, up!
-[grunting]
Watch your head. Watch your head.
[Sam] Medic! We have an injured SEAL here.
[woman speaking in Thai]
[generator starts]
[vehicle engine roars]
[engine stops]
[man] Good afternoon. I'm from Phetchabun.
I saw online
you needed 20-inch pump pipes,
so I brought some over.
-Phetchabun?
-Yes, Phetchabun.
You must have driven a long way.
Yes, it's about an eight-hour drive.
[thunder rumbles]
[rain falling]
[Titan] What do you have to do
to become a SEAL?
[Mike] In your case?
Grow another 30 centimeters.
And put on about 40 kilos, give or take.
Is that all?
[Mike] More or less.
[Baitoey] All right, boys.
Okay, so who else wants
some more of the same, hmm?
Come on, Tee. You up for another dive?
I'm all in.
Anything to get me away
from Titan and his loud mouth.
[Tee] Dom, you're up next. Biw, you too.
What the heck?
-[air tank hisses]
-[Baitoey] All right, boys.
Let's go over the three golden rules
of diving one more time.
-The first and most important rule is--
-I know!
Never hold your breath underwater?
Yeah, correct.
[Baitoey] The second
is how to clear your regulator.
-[Dom] What's the third?
-[Baitoey] Slow down.
When you get the hang of one and two,
you get three.
Okay.
Who wants to be the first to go this time?
Yeah, I can swim.
-[boy 1] How about me?
-[boy 2] Come on, Tee.
[boy 3] Come on.
It's my time.
Come, Tee.
[tense music playing]
[inhales]
[Baitoey] Go slowly.
[Baitoey] This is the way
to get you out of the cave.
[water bubbling]
[Baitoey] It's the only way home.
[spluttering]
[panting]
[Aran] Take it easy, Tee.
[vehicle engine roars]
All the farmers have agreed
to let us flood their rice paddies,
which covers an area of over 1,600 rai.
Water levels in the cave
were stable for 32 hours.
Anything else?
We got good news from Chamber Nine.
We checked the atmospheric indicator.
The oxygen levels were as we expected.
Therefore, everything
can proceed as planned.
As for the bad news,
I'll leave it for Rick and John to report.
He says you can give me the bad news.
I'm less convinced the boys can do
the dive out than I was yesterday.
It's too much, too fast.
[John] Even the team captain
seems on edge.
Uh, I just finished counting
what inventory isn't already in the cave.
We're short on tanks.
[ominous music playing]
How short?
We need 600.
And as of this morning,
we had 387 oxygen tanks on hand,
with the promise of 220 more
from a regional distributor.
[Cole] But the distributor
had made an error.
There were 20 tanks available.
-Not 220.
-[John] Oh.
[Nichols] We're 200 short.
Is there nowhere else we can get tanks?
Look, at this point, we've exhausted
all the resources in the region.
I've, I've spoken to the IndoPac command,
and they're broadening the search
to the west coast of the US, but--
There's no guarantee
we'll find what we need in time.
[Nichols] Everyone is squeezing
as hard as they can,
only keeping what they absolutely need
for their business or military needs.
There's just not that much spare capacity
and we're asking for a lot.
We keep pushing forward.
With the oxygen tanks taking the priority.
[cell phone rings]
How was it inside the cave?
[Sam] A lot tougher
than I expected. [sighs]
The path was so narrow
I could barely squeeze through
some of those tight turns.
So, when is the next dive?
Uh, I don't have one.
I have a flight in the morning to Bangkok.
As soon as I get back,
I'll be able to practice some more, okay?
What happened, Sam, huh?
Is Chet sending you home?
Or did Buddy do something?
Nothing like that.
It's not in the news yet.
There aren't enough oxygen tanks
to complete the rescue.
[softly] What?
Oh, poor kids.
-Maybe you were right.
-About what?
A break.
Those kids could really use a break.
Maybe the boys just have bad luck.
Seeing so many people join forces,
I don't want it to end like this.
I want those boys saved
as much as you do, but…
more time for us.
I'm happy you're coming home.
Forgot how hard it can be
to manage military life.
It's stressing.
I really want to come home to you.
I know you wanna help the boys though.
[gentle music playing]
WAY OUT
[women talking in Thai]
Hello! Kelly!
So glad to see you here.
Come taste my khao soi.
Come, try my khao soi.
This is my best cooking.
No, I'm not, not very hungry right now.
Give it a try first.
It's so very delicious.
[woman laughs]
Come on in.
Nid, will you watch my stall
while I talk to my friend?
[Nid] Yes, Mae Bua.
Come on in, dear.
Come, come, come!
Sit, sit.
[Bua] Sit here, please.
There.
[Bua laughs]
My khao soi is the best. [laughs]
[Bua] Dig in, dear.
I didn't think you would, um…
be working out here.
[Bua chuckling]
Where else would I go?
Mm.
I felt like
this is my only way to help.
My husband passed away many years ago.
My kids are grown up now.
I like cooking.
If I can't feed them with the rice I grow,
then I'll feed them with khao soi.
Yeah, dig in, dear. Eat up.
Go on.
[clears throat]
It's very good.
[Kelly] Thank you so much.
Yes.
I thought you would…
be angry
with… with me now.
It hasn't cost me anything
to be here doing this right now.
But…
But you gave up all your rice paddies.
And now you gave up your time
and…
and you gave your food as well.
We can only give up
the things we can afford to lose.
You found my farmland
and knew that it could be useful.
And you had the courage
to ask this old lady to sacrifice it.
Even though it was your ranger friend
that made the request.
Am I right? [chuckles]
I…
I just couldn't ask, myself.
Don't worry about it.
That's how it is.
I can give my farm,
and being here helps too.
Come on, then.
Eat it all up. [laughs]
Dig in.
Don't be shy. [chuckles]
[soothing music playing]
The boy who's swimming
is going to need a tank.
But if you do that,
one person in Chamber Nine is…
is two tanks short.
What if we flip from here to here?
No, that doesn't work either.
Master Sergeant James Nichols?
He's Nichols.
Delivery for you, sir.
Delivery for you.
[Nichols] Ask the driver
where these came from.
-Who brought these here?
-I don't know, sir.
He doesn't know.
What did you do?
[Nichols] Someone must've
heard our prayers.
I guess the mission's back on, then.
-[Nichols] Load 'em out.
-[Chet] Let's go, let's go!
[water splashes]
[footsteps approaching]
-[Baitoey] Hey, Tee.
-Hmm?
[Baitoey sighs]
[grunts]
What's wrong?
Well, your friend, Aran…
Outside he said he saw my father.
I choked up.
When my mother sent a note to me,
I thought my dad was still in Myanmar.
He works in construction there.
He can't afford to take time off.
Then I found out
he's only here because of his son.
As it is now, we barely make ends meet.
[Tee sobs]
We'll probably have to move.
It's all because of me.
I will probably have to change schools
with my sister.
[sobs] I want to be brave,
so I'll be worthy
of my family's sacrifice. [sobbing]
But I can't do it.
[sobbing] And Mali…
Wait. Mali? Who is that?
My girlfriend.
Aw!
Everyone in the team counts on me.
But I'm letting them down.
I'm letting everyone down!
-It's okay.
-I get so mad at myself.
I just feel like I can't breathe at all.
-You know…
-[Tee sobbing]
…you don't have
to carry this weight alone.
[sobbing]
[chanting]
[Baitoey] Everyone out there
is ready to sacrifice
to get all of you out of here.
Even your dad and your sister.
[sobbing]
All you have to do is one thing.
And what's that?
[equipment clattering]
[Baitoey] Breathe.
[Chet] Nobody will say
where all these tanks came from.
But my money is on the palace.
Funny. I thought I sent you two away.
Yeah, flight leaves tomorrow.
I thought we'd be more useful here
instead of staring at each other
in the hotel.
[Chet] Huh. That's good.
Oxygen is depleting
and time is ticking as we speak.
Say, up for another dive?
[tense music playing]
[watch beeps]
[exhales]
[tense music continues]
[air hisses]
[somber music playing]
[tank clangs]
[air hisses]
Wow.
[somber music continues]
[Buddy] Let's head back, Sam.
Current's getting rough.
See you on the other side.
-[water churning]
-[tank jolts]
-[dramatic music playing]
-[heartbeat racing]
-[breathing rapidly]
-[muffled speech]
[phone chimes]
[dramatic music fades]
[soothing music playing]
-[phone beeps]
-[Sam] I have good news.
Lucky, we got extra tanks.
Now we can continue the rescue.
And by the way,
I'm sorry about earlier.
I know that you…
you have made sacrifices for us.
I know, since we were married,
as a SEAL's wife,
you're asked to sacrifice
your own feelings.
-[rapid breathing]
-[tank clinks]
[muffled speech]
[Sam] You were right.
I'm so,
so lucky to have you, really, Meow.
You know me better than I know myself.
So, yeah,
I can't come home just yet.
I needed to help.
It's why I answered Chet's call
and came all the way up here.
[ethereal music playing]
It's why I can't leave.
I have to try.
-[grunting with effort]
-So many people are here and trying.
It's a powerful sight.
Even those boys are trying.
I love you, Meow.
[alarm beeping]
[gulps]
[sniffles]
[ethereal music continues]
[alarm beeping]
[poignant music playing]
[Sam] I won't be home.
Forgive me?
The thing is
I can't go home
until I'm absolutely certain
that I've given everything I can.
[poignant music continues]
-[music fades]
-[thunder rumbles, rain falling]
[tranquil music playing]